WILDAN MUJAHIDIN

Bogor, Indonesia wildan.mujahidin1@gmail.com 0899.0532.209 Linkedin Github

SUMMARY

I am a Frontend Engineer with experience in React.js, TypeScript, HTML, and Tailwind. I have worked on various projects, such as Sirloin (POS App), YSHOP (E-Commerce), Circle (social media), MyMovies, MyPokemon (Mini game), and ToDo. I have completed an immersive program in Frontend Engineering from Alterra Academy and obtained several certifications in web development, including courses in HTML & CSS, JavaScript, React, Sass, and SQL. My goal is to continue growing as a developer and contributing to meaningful projects that make a difference in people's lives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML and CSS.

Technologies: React.js, GitHub, Tailwind CSS, Jest, Firebase and Figma.
 Other: Algorithms, Computational Complexity and Problem Solving.

PROJECTS

- Sirloin is a cloud-based Point of Sales (POS) application developed using React.js that provides e-commerce functionalities enabling users to purchase products from the super admin. Additionally, the app offers stock notifications and customer management with discounts. Sirloin's user interface is styled using various libraries such as Tailwind CSS, Daisy UI, Sweetalert, and React-icons. It employs JWT for managing user login sessions, React Router for routing, Axios for API requests to the backend, Moment.js for handling dates, and Firebase for push notifications. See the source on Github.
- YSHOP is an E-Commerce website that enables CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations for products by sending API requests to the backend. It is built with React.js, Vite, React Router, React Icons, Tailwind CSS, Daisy UI, React Cookie, and Axios. See the source on Github.
- MyMovies is a website that allows users to browse movies currently playing or upcoming in theaters. The app utilizes data from the themoviedb.org API and offers a feature to add movies to favorites, which are saved in local storage. MyMovies is built with React.js and various libraries, including React Router, React Icons, Tailwind CSS, Daisy UI, and Axios. See the source on <u>Github</u>.
- MyPokemon web app game is built using React.js (tsx) and utilizes APIs from pokeapi.co to provide users with
 an immersive experience of catching and naming Pokemon. The game challenges users to capture Pokemon
 with a success rate of 50% and allows them to collect and name the creatures they catch. The app is styled
 using Tailwind CSS, Daisy UI, and React Icons libraries and utilizes React Router, Axios, and other libraries to
 interact with the backend API. See the source on Github.
- **ToDo** web app is built with React Vite and integrates with the ToDoist API to enable users to create, read, update, and delete tasks with ease. The app is styled using Tailwind CSS and Daisy UI, and utilizes Axios for API requests. See the source on Github.
- Other projects can be viewed on my <u>Github</u> page.

WORK EXPERIENCE

J&T Cargo May 2022 - August 2022 Admin Outlet Bogor, ID

• Process orders from customers, collect transaction data and assist with handling any questions or issues regarding shipping.

Qiblat Indonesia

November 2020 - January 2021

Front end React.js Intern Bogor, ID

I cloned the mobile web homepage of Bukalapak and cloned the investment app interface.

IPB University August 2019 - December 2019

Assistant Lecturer of Hardware, Networking and Programming

Bogor, ID

Assist in the teaching process.

BB Biogen February 2019 - April 2019

IT Networking Intern Bogor, ID

• Installing a wireless network and preparing a report.

PT Goodyear Indonesia, Tbk

July 2018 - August 2018

IT Support Intern Bogor, ID

• Troubleshooting computers, installing computers, and Managing IT inventory.

EDUCATION

ALTERRA ACADEMY

November 2022 - February 2023

Immersive Program, Frontend Engineering

Malang, ID

- Immersive Program Frontend Engineering is an intensive 3-month program designed to train future frontend engineers in the fundamentals of software development.
- This rigorous 60-70hr/week program has a well-documented history of developing top notch software engineers.
- Course: Pair Programming, HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Git, Github, React.js, Deployment.
- Capstone Project: Building Point of Sales (POS) App with React.js.

IPB University

September 2016 - September 2019

Diploma 3, Computer Engineering

Bogor, ID

• 6/6 semesters, 3.21/4.0 GPA cumulative.

CERTIFICATIONS

- HTML & CSS Course, JavaScript Course, React Course, Sass Course, SQL Course, Web Development Course Ruby on Rails (<u>Issued by Progate Apr 2022 and Jun 2022</u>).
- Using WordPress and Photoshop for an Online Shop Website Designer (Issued by Skill Academy Dec 2021).
- IT Essentials: PC Hardware and Software (<u>Issued by Cisco Academy Feb 2017</u>).
- HTML Fundamentals Course (<u>Issued by SoloLearn Aug 2016</u>).

LANGUAGE

- Bahasa (Native)
- English (Limited)

INTERESTS

- Staying active: I enjoy playing badminton and swimming to maintain my health and fitness.
- Music enthusiast: I have a diverse taste in music, with a particular interest in J-pop, EDM, and jazz.